<TITLE><PERSON>Desi Arnaz</PERSON></TITLE>

<PERSON>Desi Arnaz</PERSON> (born <PERSON>Desiderio Alberto Arnaz</PERSON> y de Acha III) (March 2, 1917 December 2, 1986) was a Cuban American musician, actor and television producer.

<PERSON>Desi Arnaz</PERSON> was born on March 2, 1917 in <LOCATION>Santiago de Cuba</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Cuba</LOCATION> to <PERSON>Desiderio Alberto Arnaz</PERSON> (1894-1973) and <PERSON>Dolores</PERSON> de Acha (1896-1988). His father was <LOCATION>Santiago</LOCATION>'s youngest mayor and then served in the Cuban House of Representatives. The 1933 revolution, led by <PERSON>Fulgencio Batista</PERSON>, overthrew the American-backed President <PERSON>Gerardo Machado</PERSON>, landed his father in jail for six months, and stripped his family of its wealth and power. <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON>'s father was released when <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> officials, who believed him to be neutral during the revolt, intervened on his behalf. <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> and his parents then fled to <LOCATION>Miami</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION>.

In 1939, he starred on Broadway in the successful musical Too Many Girls. He then went to <LOCATION>Hollywood</LOCATION> to appear in the 1940 movie version at RKO, which starred actress, comedienne, and his future wife <PERSON>Lucille Ball</PERSON>. At the time, he also played guitar for <PERSON>Xavier Cugat</PERSON> 

<PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> appeared in several movies in the 1940s, most notably <LOCATION>Bataan</LOCATION> (1943). Shortly after he received his draft notice, but before he was actually inducted, he injured his knee. Although he made it through boot camp, he was eventually classified for limited service, and ended up directing <ORGANIZATION>United Service Organization</ORGANIZATION> (<LOCATION>U.S.O.</LOCATION>) programs at a military hospital in the <LOCATION>San Fernando Valley</LOCATION>. In his memoirs, he recalled discovering that the first thing soldiers requested was almost invariably a glass of cold milk, so he arranged for beautiful starlets to greet the wounded soldiers as they disembarked and pour milk for them. After leaving the <ORGANIZATION>Army</ORGANIZATION>, he formed another orchestra, which was successful in live appearances and recordings. After he became engaged in television, he kept the orchestra on his payroll throughout the period he remained an active producer.

On October 15, 1951, <PERSON>Desi</PERSON> produced and starred in I Love <PERSON>Lucy</PERSON> in which he played a fictitious version of himself, <LOCATION>Cuban</LOCATION> orchestra leader <PERSON>Enrique</PERSON> "Ricky" <PERSON>Ricardo</PERSON>. His co-star was his real-life wife, <PERSON>Lucille Ball</PERSON>, who played <PERSON>Ricky</PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON>Lucy</PERSON>. Television executives had been pursuing Ball to adapt her very popular radio series My Favorite Husband for television. Ball insisted on <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> playing her on-air spouse so the two would be able to spend more time together. The original premise was for the couple to portray <PERSON>Lucy</PERSON> and <PERSON>Larry Lopez</PERSON>, a successful show business couple (he a band leader, she an actress) whose glamorous careers interfered with their efforts to maintain a normal marriage. Market research indicated, however, that this scenario would not be popular, so <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> changed it to make <PERSON>Ricky</PERSON> a struggling young orchestra leader and <PERSON>Lucy</PERSON> an ordinary housewife who had show business fantasies but no talent. <PERSON>Desi</PERSON> would often appear at, and later own, the <ORGANIZATION>Tropicana Club</ORGANIZATION> which, under his ownership, he renamed Club Babalu. Initially, the idea of having Ball and the distinctly Latino <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> portray a married couple encountered resistance as they were told that <PERSON>Desi</PERSON>'s Cuban accent and Latin style would not be agreeable to American viewers. The couple overcame these objections, however, by touring together in a live vaudeville act they developed with the help of Spanish clown <PERSON>Pepito Prez</PERSON>, together with <PERSON>Ball</PERSON>'s radio show writers. Much of the material from their vaudeville act was used in the original "I Love Lucy" pilot, including <PERSON>Lucy</PERSON>'s memorable seal routine. (The pilot originally ran as the sixth episode of the show's first season.)

With Ball, he founded Desilu Productions. At this time, most television programs were broadcast live and, as the largest markets were in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION>, the rest of the country received only kinescope images. <PERSON>Karl Freund</PERSON>, <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON>'s cameraman, developed the multiple-camera setup production style using adjacent sets that became the standard for all subsequent situation comedies to this day. The use of film enabled every station around the country to broadcast high-quality images of the show. <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> was told that it would be impossible to allow an audience onto a sound stage, but he worked with <PERSON>Freund</PERSON> to design a set that would accommodate an audience, allow filming, and also adhere to fire and safety codes.

Network executives considered the use of film an unnecessary extravagance. <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> convinced them to allow Desilu to cover all additional costs associated with the filming process, under the stipulation that Desilu owned and controlled all rights to the film. <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON>'s unprecedented arrangement is widely considered to be one of the shrewdest deals in television history. As a result of his foresight, Desilu reaped the profits from all reruns of the series.

<PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> also pushed the network to allow them to show <PERSON>Lucille Ball</PERSON> while she was pregnant. According to <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON>, the CBS network told him, "You cannot show a pregnant woman on television." <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> consulted a priest, a rabbi, and a minister, all of whom told him that there would be nothing wrong with showing a pregnant <PERSON>Lucy</PERSON> or with using the word pregnant. The network finally relented and let <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> and Ball weave the pregnancy into the story line, but remained adamant about eschewing use of pregnant, so <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> substituted expecting, pronouncing it  'spectin'  in his Cuban accent. Oddly, the official title of the episode announcing the pregnancy was "Lucy Is Enceinte," employing the French word for pregnant.

In addition to I Love <PERSON>Lucy</PERSON>, he produced December Bride, The Mothers-in-Law, The Lucy Show, Those <ORGANIZATION>Whiting Girls</ORGANIZATION>, Our Miss <PERSON>Brooks</PERSON>, The <PERSON>Danny Thomas Show</PERSON>, The <PERSON>Andy Griffith</PERSON> Show, and The Untouchables, <ORGANIZATION>Star Trek TOS</ORGANIZATION> all Top shows in their time, and the 1956 feature film Forever, Darling, in which he and Ball starred. His foresight in filming and retaining post-broadcast ownership of shows had a huge impact on the future of television syndication (reruns).

<PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ball</PERSON> avoided ethnic jokes. <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> recalled that the only exception consisted of making fun of <PERSON>Ricky Ricardo</PERSON>'s accent, and noted that even these jokes worked only when <PERSON>Lucy</PERSON>, as his wife, did the mimicking.

<PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> was patriotic; in his memoirs, the first object of thanks is the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> itself: "I know of no other country in the world", he wrote, in which "a sixteen-year-old kid, broke and unable to speak the language" could reach the success he had. Over the show's six-year run, the fortunes of the <ORGANIZATION>Ricardos</ORGANIZATION> mirror that of the archetypal 1950s American Dream: At first, they live in a tiny brownstone apartment; <PERSON>Ricky</PERSON>'s fortunes continue to improve, and they move into a slightly larger one with a view after <PERSON>Little Ricky</PERSON> is born. Later, <PERSON>Ricky</PERSON> gets his big break and goes to <LOCATION>Hollywood</LOCATION>; shortly after returning to <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION>, all of them have the chance to travel through <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION>. Finally, <PERSON>Lucy</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ricky</PERSON> head for a house in the wealthy <LOCATION>Connecticut</LOCATION> country.

<PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> married <PERSON>Lucille Ball</PERSON> on November 30, 1940, and she initiated divorce proceedings in 1944, but returned to him before the interlocutory decree became final. He and <PERSON>Ball</PERSON> are the parents of actress <PERSON>Lucie Arnaz</PERSON> (born 1951) and actor <PERSON>Desi Arnaz</PERSON>, Jr. (born 1953).

<PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON>'s marriage with <PERSON>Ball</PERSON> began to collapse under the strain of his serious problems with alcohol, drugs, and womanizing. According to his memoir, the combined pressures of managing the production company as well as supervising its day-to-day operations had greatly worsened as it grew much larger. <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> was also suffering from diverticulitis. He and <PERSON>Ball</PERSON> divorced in 1960; she was 48 and he was 43. When <PERSON>Ball</PERSON> returned to weekly television, she and <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> worked out an agreement regarding Desilu, wherein she bought him out.

<PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> married his second wife, <PERSON>Edith Mack Hirsch</PERSON>, on March 2, 1963, and greatly reduced his show business activities. He served as executive producer of <ORGANIZATION>The Mothers-in-Law</ORGANIZATION>, and during its two-year run, made four guest appearances as a <LOCATION>Spanish</LOCATION> matador, <PERSON>Seor Delgado</PERSON>. He was widowed in 1985, when his wife <PERSON>Edith</PERSON> died.

Although <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> remarried after his divorce from Ball in 1960, they remained friends. Family home movies later aired on television showed <PERSON>Ball</PERSON> and <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> playing together with their grandson, <PERSON>Simon</PERSON> (or "Simn", if <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON>'s mock protests are to be believed), shortly before <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON>'s death.

In the 1970s, <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> co-hosted a week of shows with daytime TV host/producer <PERSON>Mike Douglas</PERSON>. <PERSON>Vivian Vance</PERSON> appeared as a guest. <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> also headlined a Kraft Music Hall special on <ORGANIZATION>NBC</ORGANIZATION> that featured his two children, with a brief appearance by <PERSON>Vance</PERSON>. To promote his autobiography, A Book, <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON>, on February 21, 1976, served as a guest host on Saturday Night Live, with his son, <PERSON>Desi, Jr.</PERSON>, also appearing. The program contained spoofs of I Love <PERSON>Lucy</PERSON> and The Untouchables. He also read <PERSON>Lewis Carroll</PERSON>'s poem "Jabberwocky" in a heavy Cuban accent (he pronounced it "Habberwocky"). <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON>, <PERSON>Jr.</PERSON> played the drums and, supported by the SNL band, <PERSON>Desi</PERSON> sang both "Babalu" and another favorite from his dance band days, "Cuban Pete"; the arrangements similar to the ones used on I Love <PERSON>Lucy</PERSON>. He ended the broadcast by leading the entire cast in a raucous conga line through the SNL studio.

<PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> and his wife eventually moved to <LOCATION>Del Mar</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>California</LOCATION>, where he lived the rest of his life in semi-retirement. He owned a 45-acre (18 ha) horse breeding farm in <LOCATION>Corona</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>California</LOCATION>, and raced thoroughbreds. He contributed to charitable and non-profit organizations, including <ORGANIZATION>San Diego State University</ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON> would make a guest appearance on the TV series <PERSON>Alice</PERSON>, starring <PERSON>Linda Lavin</PERSON> and produced by I Love <PERSON>Lucy</PERSON> co-creators <PERSON>Madelyn Pugh</PERSON> (<PERSON>Madelyn Davis</PERSON>) and <PERSON>Bob Carroll</PERSON>, Jr.

<PERSON>Arnaz</PERSON>, a lifelong smoker, was diagnosed with lung cancer in early 1986. He died several months later on December 2, 1986, at age 69. Two days earlier, on what would have been his and <PERSON>Lucille</PERSON>'s 46th wedding anniversary (November 30), she telephoned him. They shared a few words, mostly "I love you's." She said "All right, honey. I'll talk to you later." She was, in fact, the last person to ever speak with <PERSON>Desi Arnaz</PERSON>. His death came just five days before <PERSON>Lucille Ball</PERSON> received the Kennedy Center Honors.

<PERSON>Desi</PERSON> was survived by his mother, <PERSON>Dolores</PERSON>, who died in 1988 at the age of 94.

<PERSON>Desi Arnaz</PERSON> has two stars on the Hollywood Walk of Fame: one at 6327 <LOCATION>Hollywood Boulevard</LOCATION> for contributions to motion pictures, and one at 6220 <LOCATION>Hollywood Boulevard</LOCATION> for television. There is a <ORGANIZATION>Lucille Ball-Desi Arnaz Center</ORGANIZATION> museum in <LOCATION>Jamestown</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> (birthplace of <PERSON>Lucille Ball</PERSON>) and a <PERSON>Desi Arnaz Bandshell</PERSON> in <LOCATION>Lucille Ball Memorial Park</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>Celoron</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> (childhood home of <PERSON>Lucille Ball</PERSON>).









<TITLE><PERSON>Boris Yeltsin</PERSON></TITLE>

<PERSON>Boris Nikolayevich Yeltsin</PERSON> (; ) (1 February 1931 23 April 2007) was the first President of the <LOCATION>Russian Federation</LOCATION>, serving from 1991 to 1999.

<PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> came to power with a wave of high expectations. On 12 June 1991 he was elected president of the Russian Soviet Federative Socialist Republic with 57% of the vote, becoming the first popularly elected president. But <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> never recovered his popularity after a series of economic and political crises in <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> in the 1990s. The <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> era was marked by widespread corruption, economic collapse, and enormous political and social problems. By the time he left office, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> had an approval rating of two percent by some estimates.

Following the dissolution of the <LOCATION>Soviet Union</LOCATION> in December 1991, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>, vowing to transform <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>'s socialist command economy into a free market economy, endorsed price liberalization and privatization programs. Due to corruption and other factors, a good deal of the national wealth fell into the hands of a relatively small group of people. 

In August 1991, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> won international plaudits for casting himself as a democrat and defying the August coup attempt of 1991 by the members of Soviet government opposed to perestroika. He left office widely unpopular with the Russian population as an ineffectual and ailing autocrat. He either acted as his own prime minister (until June 1992) or appointed men of his choice, regardless of parliament. His confrontations with parliament climaxed in the October 1993 Russian constitutional crisis, when <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> called up tanks to shell the Russian White House, blasting out his opponents in parliament. Later in 1993, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> imposed a new constitution with strong presidential powers, which was approved by referendum in December.

Just hours before the first day of 2000, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> made a surprise announcement of his resignation, leaving the presidency in the hands of <PERSON>Vladimir Putin</PERSON>.

<PERSON>Boris Yeltsin</PERSON> was born in the village of <LOCATION>Butka</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>. His father, <PERSON>Nikolay Yeltsin</PERSON>, was convicted of anti-Soviet agitation in 1934 and sentenced to hard labour in a gulag for three years. Following his release he remained unemployed for a period of time and then worked in construction. His mother, <PERSON>Klavdiya Vasilyevna Yeltsina</PERSON>, worked as a seamstress. 

<PERSON>Boris Yeltsin</PERSON> studied at <ORGANIZATION>Pushkin High School</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Berezniki</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>Perm Krai</LOCATION>. He was fond of sports (in particular skiing, gymnastics, volleyball, track and field, boxing and wrestling) despite losing the thumb and index finger of his left hand when he and some friends sneaked into a <ORGANIZATION>Red Army</ORGANIZATION> supply depot, stole several grenades, and tried to dissect them.

<PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> received his higher education at the <ORGANIZATION>Ural State Technical University</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Sverdlovsk</LOCATION>, majoring in construction, and graduated in 1955. The subject of his degree paper was "Television Tower".

From 1955 to 1957 he worked as a foreman with the building trust Uraltyazhtrubstroy and from 1957 to 1963 he worked in <LOCATION>Sverdlovsk</LOCATION>, and was promoted from construction site superintendent to chief of the <ORGANIZATION>Construction Directorate</ORGANIZATION> with the Yuzhgorstroy Trust. In 1963 he became chief engineer, and in 1965 head of the <LOCATION>Sverdlovsk</LOCATION> House-Building Combine, responsible for sewerage and technical plumbing. He joined the ranks of the <ORGANIZATION>CPSU</ORGANIZATION> nomenklatura in 1968 when he was appointed head of construction with the <ORGANIZATION>Sverdlovsk Regional Party Committee</ORGANIZATION>. In 1975 he became secretary of the regional committee in charge of the region's industrial development. In 1976 the Politburo of the <ORGANIZATION>CPSU</ORGANIZATION> promoted him to the post of the first secretary of the <ORGANIZATION>CPSU Committee of Sverdlovsk Oblast</ORGANIZATION> (effectively he became the head of one of the most important industrial regions in the <ORGANIZATION>USSR</ORGANIZATION>), he remained in this position till 1985.

<PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> was a member of the <ORGANIZATION>Communist Party</ORGANIZATION> of the <LOCATION>Soviet Union</LOCATION> (<ORGANIZATION>CPSU</ORGANIZATION>) from 1961 to July 1990, and began working in the Communist administration in 1968. He later commented on his communist views:

In 1977 as party boss in <LOCATION>Sverdlovsk</LOCATION>, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>--on orders from <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION>--ordered the destruction of the <ORGANIZATION>Ipatiev House</ORGANIZATION> where the last Russian tsar had been killed by Bolshevik troops. The Ipatiev House was demolished in one night, 27 July 1977. Also during <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s stay in <LOCATION>Sverdlovsk</LOCATION>, a <ORGANIZATION>CPSU</ORGANIZATION> palace was built which was named "White Tooth" by the residents.. During this time, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> developed connections with key people in the Soviet power structure.

He was appointed to the Politburo, and was also "Mayor" of <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION> (First Secretary of the <ORGANIZATION>CPSU Moscow City Committee</ORGANIZATION>) from 24 December 1985 to 1987. He was promoted to these high rank positions by <PERSON>Mikhail Gorbachev</PERSON> and <PERSON>Yegor Ligachev</PERSON>, who presumed that <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> would be their man. <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> was also given a country house (dacha) previously occupied by <PERSON>Gorbachev</PERSON>. During this period <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> portrayed himself as a reformer and populist (for example, he took a trolleybus to work), firing and reshuffling his staff several times. His initiatives became popular among <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION> residents.

In 1987, after a confrontation with hardliner <PERSON>Yegor Ligachev</PERSON> and <PERSON>Mikhail Gorbachev</PERSON> about <PERSON>Gorbachev</PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON>Raisa</PERSON>, meddling in affairs of the state, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> was sacked from his high ranking party positions. On 21 October 1987 at the plenary meeting of the <ORGANIZATION>Central Committee</ORGANIZATION> of the <ORGANIZATION>CPSU</ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>, without prior approval from <PERSON>Gorbachev</PERSON>, lashed out at the Politburo. He expressed his discontent with both the slow pace of reform in society and the servility shown to the General Secretary, then asked to resign from the Politburo, adding that the <ORGANIZATION>City Committee</ORGANIZATION> would decide whether he should resign from the post of first secretary of the <ORGANIZATION>Moscow City Party Committee</ORGANIZATION>. In his reply, <PERSON>Gorbachev</PERSON> accused <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> of "political immaturity" and "absolute irresponsibility", and at the plenary meeting of the <ORGANIZATION>Moscow City Party Committee</ORGANIZATION> proposed relieving <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> of his post of first secretary. Nobody backed <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>. Criticism of <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> continued on 11 November 1987 at the meeting of the <ORGANIZATION>Moscow City Party Committee</ORGANIZATION>. After <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> admitted that his speech had been a mistake, he was fired from the post of first secretary of the <ORGANIZATION>Moscow City Committee</ORGANIZATION>. He was demoted to the position of first deputy commissioner for the <ORGANIZATION>State Committee for Construction</ORGANIZATION>. After being fired, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> was hospitalized and later (confirmed by <PERSON>Nikolai Ryzhkov</PERSON>) attempted suicide. He was perturbed and humiliated but began plotting his revenge. His opportunity came with <PERSON>Gorbachev</PERSON>'s establishment of the <ORGANIZATION>Congress of People's Deputies</ORGANIZATION>. He recovered, and started intensively criticizing <PERSON>Gorbachev</PERSON>, highlighting the slow pace of reform in the <LOCATION>Soviet Union</LOCATION> as his major argument.

<PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s criticism of the Politburo and <PERSON>Gorbachev</PERSON> led to a smear campaign against him, in which examples of <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s awkward behavior were used against him. An article published in Pravda described him as being drunk at a lecture during his visit to the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION>, an allegation which appeared to be confirmed by a TV account of his speech. However, popular dissatisfaction with the regime was very strong, and these attempts to smear <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> only added to his popularity. In another incident, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> fell from a bridge. Commenting on this event, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> hinted that he was helped to fall from the bridge by the enemies of perestroika, but his opponents suggested that he was simply drunk.



In March 1989, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> was elected to the <ORGANIZATION>Congress of People's Deputies</ORGANIZATION> as the delegate from <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION> district and gained a seat on the Supreme Soviet. 

On 29 May 1990, he was elected chairman of the Presidium of the Supreme Soviet of the Russian SFSR (RSFSR), the post he held until 10 July 1991. He was supported by both democratic and conservative members of the Supreme Soviet, which sought power in the developing political situation in the country. A part of this power struggle was the opposition between power structures of the <LOCATION>Soviet Union</LOCATION> and the RSFSR. In an attempt to gain more power, on 12 June 1990, the <ORGANIZATION>Congress of People's</ORGANIZATION> Deputies of the RSFSR adopted a declaration of sovereignty and <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> quit the <ORGANIZATION>CPSU</ORGANIZATION> in July 1990.

On 12 June 1991, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> won 57% of the popular vote in the democratic presidential elections for the Russian republic, defeating <PERSON>Gorbachev</PERSON>'s preferred candidate, <PERSON>Nikolai Ryzhkov</PERSON>. In his election campaign, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> criticized the "dictatorship of the center", but did not suggest the introduction of a market economy. Instead, he said that he would put his head on the railtrack in the event of increased prices. <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> took office on 10 July.

On 18 August 1991, a coup against <PERSON>Gorbachev</PERSON> was launched by the government members opposed to perestroika headed by <PERSON>Vladimir Kryuchkov</PERSON>. <PERSON>Gorbachev</PERSON> was held in <LOCATION>Crimea</LOCATION> while <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> raced to the White House of <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> (residence of the Supreme Soviet of the RSFSR) in <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION> to defy the coup. The White House was surrounded by the military but the troops defected in the face of mass popular demonstrations. <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> responded to the coup by making a memorable speech from the turret of a tank. By 21 August most of the coup leaders had fled <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Gorbachev</PERSON> was "rescued" from <LOCATION>Crimea</LOCATION> and then returned to <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION>. <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> was subsequently hailed by his supporters around the world for rallying mass opposition to the coup.

Although restored to his position, <PERSON>Gorbachev</PERSON>'s powers were now fatally compromised. Neither union nor Russian power structures heeded his commands as support had swung over to <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>. Through the fall of 1991, the Russian government took over the union government, ministry by ministry. 

On 6 November 1991, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> issued a decree banning the <ORGANIZATION>Communist Party</ORGANIZATION> throughout the RSFSR.

In early December 1991, <LOCATION>Ukraine</LOCATION> voted for independence from the <LOCATION>Soviet Union</LOCATION>. A week later, on 8 December, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> met with <LOCATION>Ukrainian</LOCATION> president <PERSON>Leonid Kravchuk</PERSON> and the leader of <LOCATION>Belarus</LOCATION>, <PERSON>Stanislav Shushkevich</PERSON>, in <LOCATION>Belovezhskaya Pushcha</LOCATION>, where the three presidents announced the dissolution of the <LOCATION>Soviet Union</LOCATION> and that they would establish a voluntary Commonwealth of Independent States (CIS) in its place. According to <PERSON>Mikhail Gorbachev</PERSON>, the president of the <LOCATION>Soviet Union</LOCATION> at that time, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> kept the plans of the <LOCATION>Belovezhskaya</LOCATION> meeting in strict secrecy and the main goal of the dissolution of the <LOCATION>Soviet Union</LOCATION> was to get rid of <PERSON>Gorbachev</PERSON>, who by that time had started to recover his position after the events of August. <PERSON>Mikhail Gorbachev</PERSON> has also accused <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> of violating the people's will expressed in the referendum in which the majority voted to keep the <LOCATION>Soviet Union</LOCATION>.

On 24 December, the <LOCATION>Russian Federation</LOCATION> took the <LOCATION>Soviet Union</LOCATION>'s seat in the <ORGANIZATION>United Nations</ORGANIZATION>. The next day, President <PERSON>Gorbachev</PERSON> resigned and the <LOCATION>Soviet Union</LOCATION> ceased to exist, thereby ending the world's largest and most influential socialist state. Economic relations between the former <LOCATION>Soviet</LOCATION> republics were severely compromised. Millions of ethnic Russians found themselves in the newly formed foreign countries.

Just days after the dissolution of the <LOCATION>Soviet Union</LOCATION>, <PERSON>Boris Yeltsin</PERSON> resolved to embark on a program of radical economic reform, with the aim of restructuring <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>'s economic systemconverting the world's largest command economy into a free-market one. During early discussions of this transition, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s advisers debated issues of speed and sequencing, with an apparent division between those favoring a rapid approach and those favoring a gradual or slower approach.

In late 1991 <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> turned to the advice of Western economists, and Western institutions such as the <ORGANIZATION>IMF</ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION>World Bank</ORGANIZATION>, and the <ORGANIZATION>U.S. Treasury Department</ORGANIZATION>, who had developed a standard policy recipe for transition economies in the late 1980s. This policy recipe came to be known as the "<LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> Consensus" or "shock therapy", a combination of measures intended to liberalize prices and stabilize the state's budget. Such measures had been attempted in <LOCATION>Poland</LOCATION>, and advocates of "shock therapy" felt the same could be done in <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>. Some Russian policymakers were skeptical that this was the way to go, but the approach was favored by <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s deputy, <PERSON>Yegor Gaidar</PERSON>, a 35-year-old Russian economist inclined toward radical reform.

On 2 January 1992, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>, acting as his own prime minister, ordered the liberalization of foreign trade, prices, and currency. At the same time, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> followed a policy of 'macroeconomic stabilization,' a harsh austerity regime designed to control inflation. Under <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s stabilization program, interest rates were raised to extremely high levels to tighten money and restrict credit. To bring state spending and revenues into balance, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> raised new taxes heavily, cut back sharply on government subsidies to industry and construction, and made steep cuts to state welfare spending.

In early 1992, prices skyrocketed throughout <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>, and deep credit crunch shut down many industries and brought about a protracted depression. The reforms devastated the living standards of much of the population, especially the groups dependent on Soviet-era state subsidies and welfare entitlement programs. Through the 1990s, <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>'s GDP fell by 50 percent, vast sectors of the economy were wiped out, inequality and unemployment grew dramatically, while incomes fell. Hyperinflation, caused by the <ORGANIZATION>Central Bank of Russia</ORGANIZATION>'s loose monetary policy, wiped out a lot of personal savings, and tens of millions of Russians were plunged into poverty.

Some economists argue that in the 1990s <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> suffered an economic downturn more severe than the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> or <LOCATION>Germany</LOCATION> had undergone six decades earlier in the Great Depression. Russian commentators and even some Western economists, such as <PERSON>Marshall Goldman</PERSON>, widely blamed <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s Western-backed economic program for the country's disastrous economic performance in the 1990s. Many politicians began to quickly distance themselves from the program. In February 1992, <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>'s vice president, <PERSON>Alexander Rutskoy</PERSON> denounced the <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> program as "economic genocide." By 1993 conflict over the reform direction escalated between <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> on the one side, and the opposition to radical economic reform in <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>'s parliament on the other.

Also throughout 1992, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> wrestled with the Supreme Soviet and the <ORGANIZATION>Congress of People's</ORGANIZATION> Deputies for control over government, government policy, government banking and property. In the course of 1992, the speaker of the Russian Supreme Soviet, <PERSON>Ruslan Khasbulatov</PERSON>, came out in opposition to the reforms, despite claiming to support <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s overall goals. In December 1992, the <ORGANIZATION>7th Congress of People's Deputies</ORGANIZATION> succeeded in turning down the Yeltsin-backed candidacy of <PERSON>Yegor Gaidar</PERSON> for the position of Russian prime minister. Eventually, on 14 December, <PERSON>Viktor Chernomyrdin</PERSON>, seen as a compromise figure, was confirmed in the office.

The conflict escalated on 20 March 1993 when <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>, in a televised address to the nation, announced that he was going to assume certain "special powers" in order to implement his program of reforms. In response, the hastily-called <ORGANIZATION>9th Congress of People's Deputies</ORGANIZATION> attempted to remove <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> from presidency through impeachment on 26 March 1993. <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s opponents gathered more than 600 votes for impeachment, but fell 72 votes short of the required two-thirds majority. On 21 September 1993 <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> announced in a televised address his decision to disband the Supreme Soviet and <ORGANIZATION>Congress of People's</ORGANIZATION> Deputies by decree.

In his address <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> declared his intent to rule by decree until the election of the new parliament and a referendum on a new constitution, triggering the constitutional crisis of October 1993. On the night after <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s televised address, the Supreme Soviet declared <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> removed from presidency, by virtue of his breaching the constitution, and Vice-President <PERSON>Alexander Rutskoy</PERSON> was sworn in as the acting president.

Between 2124 September <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> was confronted by significant popular unrest, encouraging the defenders of the parliament. <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION> saw what amounted to a spontaneous mass uprising of anti-Yeltsin demonstrators numbering in the tens of thousands marching in the streets resolutely seeking to aid forces defending the parliament building. The demonstrators were protesting the new and terrible living conditions under <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>. Since 1989 GDP had declined by half. Corruption was rampant, violent crime was skyrocketing, medical services were collapsing, food and fuel were increasingly scarce and life expectancy was falling for all but a tiny handful of the population; moreover, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> was increasingly getting the blame.

By early October, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> had secured the support of <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>'s army and ministry of interior forces. In a massive show of force, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> called up tanks to shell the Russian White House, <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>'s parliament building, blasting out his opponents. As a result, hundreds died and thousands were wounded. 

As Supreme Soviet was dissolved, in December 1993 elections to the newly established parliament, the State Duma, were held. Candidates associated with <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s economic policies were overwhelmed by a huge anti-Yeltsin vote, the bulk of which was divided between the <ORGANIZATION>Communist Party</ORGANIZATION> and ultra-nationalists. The referendum, however, held at the same time, approved the new constitution, which significantly expanded the powers of the president, giving <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> a right to appoint the members of the government, to dismiss the prime minister and, in some cases, to dissolve the Duma.



In December 1994, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> ordered the military invasion of <LOCATION>Chechnya</LOCATION> in an attempt to restore <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION>'s control over the separatist republic. Nearly two years later <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> withdrew federal forces from the devastated <LOCATION>Chechnya</LOCATION> under a 1996 peace agreement brokered by <PERSON>Alexander Lebed</PERSON>, then <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s security chief. The peace deal allowed <LOCATION>Chechnya</LOCATION> greater autonomy but not full independence.

The decision to launch the war in <LOCATION>Chechnya</LOCATION> dismayed many in the West. TIME magazine wrote: "Then, what was to be made of <PERSON>Boris Yeltsin</PERSON>? Clearly he could no longer be regarded as the <ORGANIZATION>democratic</ORGANIZATION> hero of Western myth. But had he become an old- style communist boss, turning his back on the <ORGANIZATION>democratic</ORGANIZATION> reformers he once championed and throwing in his lot with militarists and ultranationalists? Or was he a befuddled, out-of-touch chief being manipulated, knowingly or unwittingly, by well, by whom exactly? If there was to be a dictatorial coup, would <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> be its victim or its leader?"



Following the collapse of the <LOCATION>Soviet Union</LOCATION>, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> promoted privatization as a way of spreading ownership of shares in former state enterprises as widely as possible to create political support for his economic reforms. In the West, privatization was viewed as the key to the transition from communism in <LOCATION>Eastern Europe</LOCATION>, ensuring a quick dismantling of the Soviet-era command economy to make way for 'free market reforms.' In the early 1990s, <PERSON>Anatoly Chubais</PERSON>, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s deputy for economic policy, emerged as a leading advocate of privatization in <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>.

In late 1992, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> launched a program of free vouchers as a way to give mass privatization a jump-start. Under the program, all Russian citizens were issued vouchers, each with a nominal value of around 10,000 rubles, for purchase of shares of select state enterprises. Although each citizen initially received a voucher of equal face value, within months most of them converged in the hands of intermediaries who were ready to buy them for cash right away.

In 1995, as <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> struggled to finance <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>'s growing foreign debt and gain support from the Russian business elite for his bid in the spring 1996 presidential elections, the Russian president prepared for a new wave of privatization offering stock shares in some of <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>'s most valuable state enterprises in exchange for bank loans. The program was promoted as a way of simultaneously speeding up privatization and ensuring the government a much-needed infusion of cash for its operating needs.

However, the deals were effectively giveaways of valuable state assets to a small group of tycoons in finance, industry, energy, telecommunications, and the media who came to be known as "oligarchs" in the mid-1990s. By summer 1996, substantial ownership shares over major firms were acquired at very low prices by a handful of people. <PERSON>Boris Berezovsky</PERSON>, who controlled major stakes in several banks and the national media, emerged as one of <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s most prominent backers. Along with <PERSON>Berezovsky</PERSON>, <PERSON>Mikhail Khodorkovsky</PERSON>, <PERSON>Vladimir Potanin</PERSON>, <PERSON>Vladimir Bogdanov</PERSON>, <PERSON>Rem Viakhirev</PERSON>, <PERSON>Vagit Alekperov</PERSON>, <PERSON>Alexander Smolensky</PERSON>, <PERSON>Victor Vekselberg</PERSON>, <PERSON>Mikhail Fridman</PERSON> and a few years later <PERSON>Roman Abramovich</PERSON>, were habitually mentioned in the media as <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>'s oligarchs.

On 5 December 1991, Senator <PERSON>Jesse Helms</PERSON>, ranking member of the Minority Staff of the <ORGANIZATION>U.S. Senate Committee</ORGANIZATION> on Foreign Relations, wrote to <PERSON>Boris Yeltsin</PERSON> concerning <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> servicemen who were POWs or MIAs. "The status of thousands and thousands of American servicemen who are held by Soviet and other Communist forces, and who were never repatriated after every major war this century, is of grave concern to the American people." 

<PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> would ultimately respond with a statement made on 15 June 1992, while being interviewed aboard his presidential jet on his way to the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION>, "Our archives have shown that it is true some of them were transferred to the territory of the <LOCATION>U.S.S.R.</LOCATION> and were kept in labor camps... We can only surmise that some of them may still be alive." On 10 December 1991, just five days after Senator <PERSON>Helms</PERSON> had written <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> concerning American servicemen, he again wrote to <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>, this time concerning KAL 007. 

"One of the greatest tragedies of the Cold War was the shoot-down of the <ORGANIZATION>Korean Airlines</ORGANIZATION> Flight 007 by the Armed Forces of what was then the <LOCATION>Soviet Union</LOCATION> on 1 September 1983... The KAL-007 tragedy was one of the most tense incidences of the entire Cold War. However, now that relations between our two nations have improved substantially, I believe that it is time to resolve the mysteries surrounding this event. 

Clearing the air on this issue could help further to improve relations." In March of 1992, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> would hand over KAL 007's Black Box without its tapes to Korean President <PERSON>Roh Tae-Woo</PERSON> at the end of the plenary session of the <ORGANIZATION>Korean National Assembly</ORGANIZATION> with this statement, "We apologize for the tragedy and are trying to settle some unsolved issues."

<PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> would ultimately respond on 8 January 1992 by handing over to the <ORGANIZATION>International Civil Aviation Organization</ORGANIZATION> (<ORGANIZATION>ICAO</ORGANIZATION>) of the <ORGANIZATION>United Nations</ORGANIZATION> what the Russians had for so many years denied possessing: the tapes of the <ORGANIZATION>KAL 007</ORGANIZATION>'s "Black Box" (its Digital Flight Data Recorder and Cockpit Voice Recorder). 

The openness of <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> about POW/MIA and <ORGANIZATION>KAL</ORGANIZATION> 007 matters may also have signaled his willingness for more openness to the West. In 1992, which he labelled the "window of opportunity", he was willing to discuss biological weapons with the <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> but never admitted that the <LOCATION>Sverdlovsk</LOCATION> anthrax leak of 2 April 1979 had been caused as a result of a mishap at a military facility. The Russian government has maintained that the cause was contaminated meat. The true number of victims in the anthrax outbreak at <LOCATION>Sverdlovsk</LOCATION>, about  east of <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION>, is not known.

In February 1996, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> announced that he would seek a second term in the spring 1996 Russian presidential election. The announcement followed weeks of speculation that <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> was at the end of his political career because of his health problems and growing unpopularity in <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>. At the time <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> was recuperating from a series of heart attacks. Domestic and international observers also noted his occasionally erratic behaviour. When campaigning opened at the beginning of 1996, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s popularity was close to zero. Meanwhile, the opposition <ORGANIZATION>Communist Party of the Russian Federation</ORGANIZATION> had already gained ground in parliamentary voting on 17 December 1995, and its candidate, <PERSON>Gennady Zyuganov</PERSON>, had a strong grass roots organization, especially in the rural areas and small towns, and appealed effectively to memories of the old days of Soviet prestige on the international stage and the socialist domestic order.

Panic struck the <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> team when opinion polls suggested that the ailing president could not win; some members of his entourage urged him to cancel presidential elections and effectively rule as dictator from then on. Instead, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> changed his campaign team, assigning a key role to his daughter, <PERSON>Tatyana Dyachenko</PERSON>, and appointing <PERSON>Chubais</PERSON> as campaign manager. <PERSON>Chubais</PERSON>, acting as both <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s campaign manager and adviser on <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>'s privatisation programme, used his control of the privatisation programme as an instrument of <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s reelection campaign.

In the spring of 1996, <PERSON>Chubais</PERSON> and <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> recruited a team of a handful of financial and media oligarchs to bankroll the <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> campaign and guaranteed favorable media coverage the president on national television and in leading newspapers. In return, <PERSON>Chubais</PERSON> allowed well-connected Russian business leaders to acquire majority stakes in some of <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>'s most valuable state-owned assets. The media painted a picture of a fateful choice for <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>, between <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> and a "return to totalitarianism." The oligarchs even played up the threat of civil war if a Communist were elected president.Yeltsin campaigned energetically, dispelling concerns about his health, and maintained a high media profile. To boost his popularity, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> promised to abandon some his more unpopular economic reforms, boost welfare spending, end the war in <LOCATION>Chechnya</LOCATION>, and pay wage and pension arrears. <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s campaign also got a boost from the announcement of a $10 billion loan to the Russian government from the International Monetary Fund.

<PERSON>Zyuganov</PERSON>, who lacked <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s resources and financial backing, saw his strong initial lead whittle away. After the first round on 16 June <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> appointed a highly popular candidate <PERSON>Alexander Lebed</PERSON>, who came in third in the first round, Secretary of the <ORGANIZATION>Security Council of Russia</ORGANIZATION>, sacked at the latter's behest defence minister <PERSON>Pavel Grachev</PERSON> and on 20 June sacked a number of his siloviki, one of them being his chief of presidential security <PERSON>Alexander Korzhakov</PERSON>, viewed by many as <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s minence grise.

In the run-off on 3 July, with a turnout of 68.9%, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> won 53.8% of the vote and <PERSON>Zyuganov</PERSON> 40.3%, with the rest (5.9%) voting "against all".

In his second term, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> was unable to follow through on most of his campaign promises, except for ending the Chechen war, which was halted for most of the period.



In July 1996, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> was re-elected as president with financial support from influential business oligarchs who owed their wealth to their connections with <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s administration. Despite only gaining 35% of the first round vote in the 1996 elections, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> defeated his communist rival <PERSON>Gennady Zyuganov</PERSON> with 54% in the runoff election. Later that year, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> underwent an emergency quintuple heart bypass surgery and remained in the hospital for months.

During <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s presidency, <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> received US$ 40 billion in funds from the <ORGANIZATION>IMF</ORGANIZATION> and other international lending organizations. However, his opponents allege that most of these funds were stolen by people from <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s circle and placed in foreign banks.

In 1998, a political and economic crisis emerged when <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s government defaulted on its debts, causing financial markets to panic and the ruble to collapse in the 1998 financial crisis.

During the 1999 <LOCATION>Kosovo</LOCATION> war, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> strongly opposed the <ORGANIZATION>NATO</ORGANIZATION> military campaign against <LOCATION>Yugoslavia</LOCATION>, and warned of possible <LOCATION>Russian</LOCATION> intervention if <ORGANIZATION>NATO</ORGANIZATION> deployed ground troops to <LOCATION>Kosovo</LOCATION>. In televised comments he stated: "I told <ORGANIZATION>NATO</ORGANIZATION>, the Americans, the Germans: Don't push us toward military action. Otherwise there will be a European war for sure and possibly world war."

On 15 May 1999, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> survived another attempt of impeachment, this time by the democratic and communist opposition in the State Duma. He was charged with several unconstitutional activities, including the signing of the Belavezha Accords, dissolving the <LOCATION>Soviet Union</LOCATION> in December 1991, the coup-d'tat in October 1993, and initiating the war in <LOCATION>Chechnya</LOCATION> in 1994. None of these charges received the two-thirds majority of the Duma which was required to initiate the process of impeachment of the president.

On 9 August 1999 <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> fired his prime minister, <PERSON>Sergei Stepashin</PERSON>, and for the fourth time, fired his entire cabinet. In <PERSON>Stepashin</PERSON>'s place he appointed <PERSON>Vladimir Putin</PERSON>, relatively unknown at that time, and announced his wish to see <PERSON>Putin</PERSON> as his successor.

In late 1999 <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> and President <PERSON>Clinton</PERSON> openly disagreed on the war in <LOCATION>Chechnya</LOCATION>. At the November meeting of the Organization for Security and Cooperation in <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION>, <PERSON>Clinton</PERSON> pointed his finger at <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> and demanded he halt bombing attacks that had resulted in many civilian casualties. <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> immediately left the conference.

In December while visiting <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> to seek support on <LOCATION>Chechnya</LOCATION>, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> replied to <PERSON>Clintons</PERSON> criticism of a Russian ultimatum to citizens of <LOCATION>Grozney</LOCATION>. He bluntly pronounced: "Yesterday, <PERSON>Clinton</PERSON> permitted himself to put pressure on <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>. It seems he has for a minute, for a second, for half a minute, forgotten that <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> has a full arsenal of nuclear weapons. He has forgotten about that." <PERSON>Clinton</PERSON> dismissed <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s comments stating: "I didn't think he'd forgotten that <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> was a great power when he disagreed with what I did in <LOCATION>Kosovo</LOCATION>." It fell to <PERSON>Vladimir Putin</PERSON> to downplay <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s comments and present reassurances about <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> and Russian relations.

On 31 December 1999, in a surprise announcement aired at 12:00 noon on Russian television and taped in the morning of the same day, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> said he had resigned and Prime Minister <PERSON>Vladimir Putin</PERSON> had taken over as acting president, with elections due to take place on 26 March 2000. <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> asked for forgiveness for what he acknowledged were errors of his rule, and said <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> needed to enter the new century with new political leaders. <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> said: "I want to beg forgiveness for your dreams that never came true. And also I would like to beg forgiveness not to have justified your hopes."

According to numerous reports, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> struggled with alcoholism. The subject made headlines abroad during <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s visit to the <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> in 1989 for a series of lectures on social and political life in the <LOCATION>Soviet Union</LOCATION>. That trip was described by a report in the Italian newspaper <ORGANIZATION>La Repubblica</ORGANIZATION>. The article reported that <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> often appeared drunk in public. The article was reprinted by Pravda. <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s alleged alcoholism was also the subject of media discussion following his meeting with <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> Deputy Secretary of State <PERSON>Strobe Talbott</PERSON> following <PERSON>Clinton</PERSON>'s inauguration in 1993 and after his flight stop-over at <LOCATION>Shannon Airport</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Ireland</LOCATION> in September 1994 when the waiting Irish Taoiseach (prime minister) <PERSON>Albert Reynolds</PERSON> was told that <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> was unwell and would not be leaving the aircraft.

According to former Deputy Prime Minister of <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> <PERSON>Boris Nemtsov</PERSON>, the bizarre behavior of <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> resulted from "strong drugs" given to him by <PERSON>Kremlin</PERSON>'s doctors, which were incompatible even with a small amount of alcohol. This was discussed by journalist <PERSON>Yelena Tregubova</PERSON> from the "Kremlin's pool" in connection with an episode during <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s visit to <LOCATION>Stockholm</LOCATION> in 1997 when <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> suddenly started talking nonsense (he allegedly told his bemused audience that Swedish meatballs reminded him of <PERSON>Bjrn Borg</PERSON>'s face), lost his balance, and almost fell down on the podium after drinking a single glass of Champagne <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>, in his memoirs, claimed no recollection of the event but did however make a passing reference to the incident when he met <PERSON>Borg</PERSON> a year later at The World Circle Kabaddi Cup in <LOCATION>Hamilton</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Ontario</LOCATION>, where the pair had been invited to present the trophy. Similarly, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> made a hasty withdrawal from the funeral of <PERSON>Hussein</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Jordan</LOCATION> in February 1999. (Russian: . ., M., Ad <PERSON>Marginem</PERSON>, 2003 ISBN 5-93321-073-0 Full text in Russian. German translation. 

After <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s death, a Dutch neurosurgeon revealed that his team was secretly flown to <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION> to operate on <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> in 1999. <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> suffered from an unspecified neurological disorder that affected his sense of balance, causing him to wobble as if in a drunken state; the goal of the operation was to reduce the pain.

<PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s personal and health problems received a great deal of attention in the global press. As the years went on, he was often viewed as an increasingly unstable leader, rather than the inspiring figure he was once seen as. The possibility that he might die in office was often discussed.Starting in the last years of his presidential term, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s primary residence was the Gorki-9 presidential dacha west of <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION>. He made frequent stays at the nearby government sanatorium in <LOCATION>Barvikha</LOCATION>.

<PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> maintained a low profile after his resignation, making almost no public statements or appearances. However, on 13 September 2004, following the <LOCATION>Beslan</LOCATION> school hostage crisis and nearly-concurrent terrorist attacks in <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION>, <PERSON>Putin</PERSON> launched an initiative to replace the election of regional governors with a system whereby they would be directly appointed by the president and approved by regional legislatures. <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>, together with <PERSON>Mikhail Gorbachev</PERSON>, publicly criticized <PERSON>Putin</PERSON>'s plan as a step away from democracy in <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> and a return to the centrally-run political apparatus of the Soviet era.

In September 2005, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> underwent a hip operation in <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION> after breaking his femur in a fall while vacationing on the Italian island of <LOCATION>Sardinia</LOCATION>.

On 1 February 2006, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> celebrated his 75th birthday. He used this occasion as an opportunity to criticize a "monopolistic" <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> foreign policy, and to state that <PERSON>Vladimir Putin</PERSON> was the right choice for <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>. He also disputed accusations of corruption.

<PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> also used his retirement to pursue his considerable love of tennis. He was a frequent fixture at tournaments held in <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>, notably Russian Davis Cup and Federation Cup team events. Far from a passive supporter like many VIPs who attend sports events, <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> gained a reputation as an animated fan, cheering and jumping in support of the Russians. When the Russian men won the Davis Cup in 2002 and 2006 <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> descended the stands to celebrate with the players, group hugging the team.

Following his death in April 2007, his widow, <PERSON>Naina</PERSON>, attended in <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s place the final of that year's Federation Cup, in which <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>'s women comprehensively beat <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION>.

<PERSON>Boris Yeltsin</PERSON> died of congestive heart failure on 23 April 2007 at the age of 76. According to experts quoted by <ORGANIZATION>Komsomolskaya Pravda</ORGANIZATION>, the onset of <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s condition was due to his visit to Jordan between 25 March and 2 April. He was buried in the Novodevichy Cemetery on 25 April 2007, following a period during which his body had lain in state in the Cathedral of Christ the Saviour in <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION>. <PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> was the first Russian statesman in 113 years to be buried in a church ceremony, after Emperor <PERSON>Alexander III</PERSON>. He was also the first leader in Russian and Soviet history to die quietly in retirement having overseen a peaceful transfer to his successor, <PERSON>Lenin</PERSON> being forced to retire by illness and <PERSON>Khrushchev</PERSON> being ousted in a coup. 

President <PERSON>Putin</PERSON> declared the day of his funeral a national day of mourning, with flags flown at half-staff and all entertainment programs suspended for the day. 

<PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON> is survived by his wife, <PERSON>Naina Iosifovna Yeltsina</PERSON>, whom he married in 1956, and their two daughters <PERSON>Yelena</PERSON> and <PERSON>Tatyana</PERSON>, born in 1957 and 1959 respectively.

<PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>'s "presidency has inscribed him forever in <LOCATION>Russian</LOCATION> and in world history." ... "A new democratic <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> was born during his time: a free, open and peaceful country. A state in which the power truly does belong to the people." ... "the first President of Russias strength consisted in the mass support of Russian citizens for his ideas and aspirations. Thanks to the will and direct initiative of President <PERSON>Boris Yeltsin</PERSON> a new constitution, one which declared human rights a supreme value, was adopted. It gave people the opportunity to freely express their thoughts, to freely choose power in <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>, to realise their creative and entrepreneurial plans. This Constitution permitted us to begin building a truly effective Federation." ... "We knew (<PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>) as a brave and a warm-hearted, spiritual person. He was an upstanding and courageous national leader. And he was always very honest and frank while defending his position." ... "(<PERSON>Yeltsin</PERSON>) assumed full responsibility for everything he called for, for everything he aspired to. For everything he tried to do and did do for the sake of <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>, for the sake of millions of Russians. And he invariably took upon himself, let it in his heart, all the trials and tribulations of <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>, peoples difficulties and problems."Shortly after the news broke, former Soviet leader <PERSON>Mikhail Gorbachev</PERSON> issued a statement, saying:"I offer my deepest condolences to the family of a man on whose shoulders rested many great deeds for the good of the country and serious mistakesa tragic fate".











<TITLE><PERSON>Cary Elwes</PERSON></TITLE>

<PERSON>Ivan Simon Cary Elwes</PERSON> (born October 26, 1962) is an English actor credited as <PERSON>Cary Elwes</PERSON>, known for his performances in Another Country, The Princess Bride, , Hot Shots!, Glory, Liar, Liar and Saw.

<PERSON>Elwes</PERSON> was born in <LOCATION>London</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>England</LOCATION>. His advertising agent father <PERSON>Dominic Elwes</PERSON> and grandfather <PERSON>Simon Elwes</PERSON> were very well-known British portrait painters. His father had moved in the circles of high society (and been friends with Lord <PERSON>Lucan</PERSON> and <PERSON>Lady Annabel Goldsmith</PERSON> to whom he was also related) before he committed suicide in 1975. His mother, interior designer and shipping heiress <PERSON>Tessa Georgina Kennedy</PERSON>, is of Croatian and Anglo-Irish descent; she eloped with his father in 1958 at age nineteen to great scandal. <PERSON>Elwes</PERSON>'s mother later re-married to Hollywood executive, <PERSON>Elliott Kastner</PERSON>, from whom he has a half-sister, <PERSON>Milica Kastner</PERSON> and half-brother <PERSON>Dillon Kastner</PERSON>.

<PERSON>Elwes</PERSON> descends from a devoutly Roman Catholic recusant family on his father's side (originally known as the "Cary-Elwes" family, but now many branches of the family are now simply known as "Elwes") which includes noted British monks and bishops, such as <PERSON>Abbott Columba Cary-Elwes</PERSON>, Archbishop <PERSON>Dudley Cary-Elwes</PERSON> and <PERSON>Father Luke Cary-Elwes</PERSON>. He himself was an altar boy at the Brompton Oratory. He is also said to be distantly related to <PERSON>Guilford Dudley</PERSON>, whom he played in the movie Lady <PERSON>Jane</PERSON>. 

<PERSON>Elwes</PERSON> attended <ORGANIZATION>West Acre House</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>Harrow School</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>England</LOCATION>, and <PERSON>Sarah Lawrence College</PERSON> in <LOCATION>Yonkers</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION>, where he studied, among other acting-related subjects, German Expressionist Film.

<PERSON>Elwes</PERSON> has also appeared on television. In 1996, he played a bit part as "<PERSON>David Libner</PERSON>" on the hit show Seinfeld, opposite Debra Messing. In 1998, he played Astronaut <PERSON>Michael Collins</PERSON> in the Golden Globe Award-winning <ORGANIZATION>HBO</ORGANIZATION> miniseries From the Earth To the Moon. In 1999, he guest starred as Dr. <PERSON>John York</PERSON> in the Ripper episode of the television series The Outer Limits. He earned two Golden Satellite Award nominations for his performances in the television films The Pentagon Wars and Uprising. He had a recurring role in the final season (2001-2002) of The X-Files as <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> Assistant Director <PERSON>Brad Follmer</PERSON>. <PERSON>Chris Carter</PERSON>, creator of the X-Files, wrote the character especially for him. In 2004, he received great praise with his portrayal of serial killer <PERSON>Ted Bundy</PERSON> in the <ORGANIZATION>A&E Network</ORGANIZATION> film The Riverman, which was based on the book The Riverman: <PERSON>Ted Bundy</PERSON> and I Hunt for the Green River Killer written by <PERSON>Robert D. Keppel</PERSON>. The Riverman became one of the highest rated original movies in the networks history and garnered a prestigious BANFF Rockie Award nomination. In 2005 he again received critical acclaim, internationally, with his portrayal of the young, pre-Pope <PERSON>John Paul II</PERSON> in the CBS made-for-TV movie epic Pope <PERSON>John Paul</PERSON> II. This epic was highly successful not only in <LOCATION>North America</LOCATION>, but also in <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION>, where it broke box office records in the late pope's native <LOCATION>Poland</LOCATION> and became the first film ever to break $1 million (GBP588,200) in three days. 

His voice-over works include the narrator in <PERSON>James Patterson</PERSON>'s audio book The Jester as well as characters in film and television animations such as Quest for Camelot, Hercules, Batman Beyond, and the English versions of the Japanese films <PERSON>Porco Rosso</PERSON>, Whisper of the Heart, and The Cat Returns. For the 2004 video game The Bard's Tale, he served as scriptwriter, improviser, and voice actor of the main character The Bard.

He has also performed in the <PERSON>Bob Balaban-directed</PERSON> off-Broadway dramatic stage play The Exonerated in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> during the March 18-23, 2003 week run. 

In August 2005, he filed a lawsuit against his management firm and the producers of Saw. He alleged that he was promised "a minimum of one percent of the producers' net profits" and did not receive the full amount as promised. 

<PERSON>Elwes</PERSON> has volunteered as an actor with the <ORGANIZATION>Young Storytellers Program</ORGANIZATION>. 

He made an uncredited appearance as <PERSON>Lester Persky</PERSON> the man who introduced <PERSON>Andy Warhol</PERSON> to <PERSON>Edie Sedgwick</PERSON> in the 2006 film Factory Girl. In 2007, he made a guest appearance on .

<PERSON>Elwes</PERSON> and <PERSON>Lisa Marie Kurbikoff</PERSON> met in 1991 at a <LOCATION>Malibu</LOCATION> chili cook-off. He became engaged to <LOCATION>Kurbikoff</LOCATION> in 1997 in <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> and they wed in 2000. <PERSON>Elwes</PERSON> has two brothers, <PERSON>Cassian</PERSON> and <PERSON>Damian</PERSON>, and a half-sister <PERSON>Milica</PERSON>, who are all involved in the entertainment industry. He has been active in fighting for the rights of Native Americans.

<PERSON>Lisa Marie Elwes</PERSON> gave birth to the couple's daughter, <PERSON>Dominique</PERSON>, born on April 24, 2007 at 10:41 p.m. at <ORGANIZATION>Cedars Sinai Medical Center</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Los Angeles</LOCATION>. She weighed 7 lbs., 2 oz.







<TITLE><PERSON>Abraham Lincoln</PERSON></TITLE>

<PERSON>Abraham Lincoln</PERSON> (February 12, 1809 - April 15, 1865), the sixteenth President of the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION>, successfully led his country through its greatest internal crisis, the American Civil War, only to be assassinated as the war was coming to an end. Before becoming the first Republican elected to the Presidency, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> was a lawyer, an <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION> state legislator, a member of the <ORGANIZATION>United States House of Representatives</ORGANIZATION>, and an unsuccessful candidate for election to the <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION>.

As an outspoken opponent of the expansion of slavery in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION>, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> won the <ORGANIZATION>Republican Party</ORGANIZATION> nomination in 1860 and was elected president later that year. During his time in office, he contributed to the effort to preserve the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> by leading the defeat of the secessionist <ORGANIZATION>Confederate States of America</ORGANIZATION> in the American Civil War. He introduced measures that resulted in the abolition of slavery, issuing his Emancipation Proclamation in 1863 and promoting the passage of the Thirteenth Amendment to the Constitution, which passed <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> before <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON>'s death and was ratified by the states later in 1865.

<PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> closely supervised the victorious war effort, especially the selection of top generals, including <PERSON>Ulysses S. Grant</PERSON>. Historians have concluded that he handled the factions of the <ORGANIZATION>Republican Party</ORGANIZATION> well, bringing leaders of each faction into his cabinet and forcing them to cooperate. <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> successfully defused a war scare with the <LOCATION>United Kingdom</LOCATION> in 1861. Under his leadership, the Union took control of the border slave states at the start of the war. Additionally, he managed his own reelection in the 1864 presidential election.

Opponents of the war (also known as "Copperheads") criticized <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> for refusing to compromise on the slavery issue. Conversely, the Radical Republicans, an abolitionist faction of the <ORGANIZATION>Republican Party</ORGANIZATION>, criticized him for moving too slowly in abolishing slavery. Even with these road blocks, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> successfully rallied public opinion through his rhetoric and speeches; his <ORGANIZATION>Gettysburg Address</ORGANIZATION> is but one example of this. At the close of the war, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> held a moderate view of Reconstruction, seeking to speedily reunite the nation through a policy of generous reconciliation. His assassination in 1865 was the first presidential assassination in <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> history and made him a martyr for the ideal of national unity.



<PERSON>Abraham Lincoln</PERSON> was born on February 12, 1809, to <PERSON>Thomas Lincoln</PERSON> and <PERSON>Nancy Hanks</PERSON>, two uneducated farmers, in a one-room log cabin on the  Sinking Spring Farm, in southeast <LOCATION>Hardin County</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Kentucky</LOCATION> (now part of <LOCATION>LaRue County</LOCATION>), making him the first president born outside the original Thirteen Colonies. <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON>'s ancestor <PERSON>Samuel Lincoln</PERSON> had arrived in <LOCATION>Hingham</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Massachusetts</LOCATION> in the 17th century, but his descendants had gradually moved west, from <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION> to <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION> and then westward to the frontier.

For some time, <PERSON>Thomas Lincoln</PERSON>, <PERSON>Abraham</PERSON>'s father, was a respected and relatively affluent citizen of the <LOCATION>Kentucky</LOCATION> backcountry. He had purchased the Sinking Spring Farm in December 1808 for $200 cash and assumption of a debt. The family belonged to a Hardshell Baptist church, although <PERSON>Abraham</PERSON> himself never joined their church, or any other church for that matter.

In 1816, the <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> family was forced to make a new start in <LOCATION>Perry County</LOCATION> (now in <LOCATION>Spencer County</LOCATION>), <LOCATION>Indiana</LOCATION>. He later noted that this move was "partly on account of slavery," and partly because of difficulties with land deeds in <LOCATION>Kentucky</LOCATION>: Unlike land in the <LOCATION>Northwest Territory</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Kentucky</LOCATION> never had a proper <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> survey, and farmers often had difficulties proving title to their property.

When <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> was nine, his mother, then 34 years old, died of milk sickness. Soon afterwards, his father remarried to <PERSON>Sarah Bush Johnston</PERSON>. <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> was affectionate toward his stepmother, whom he would call "Mother" for the rest of his life, but he was distant from his father.

In 1830, after more economic and land-title difficulties in <LOCATION>Indiana</LOCATION>, the family settled on public land in <LOCATION>Macon County</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION>. The following winter was desolate and especially brutal, and the family considered moving back to <LOCATION>Indiana</LOCATION>. The following year, when his father relocated the family to a new homestead in <LOCATION>Coles County</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION>, 22-year-old <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> struck out on his own, canoeing down the <LOCATION>Sangamon River</LOCATION> to the village of <LOCATION>New Salem</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>Sangamon County</LOCATION>. Later that year, hired by <LOCATION>New Salem</LOCATION> businessman <PERSON>Denton Offutt</PERSON> and accompanied by friends, he took goods from <LOCATION>New Salem</LOCATION> to <LOCATION>New Orleans</LOCATION> via flatboat on the <LOCATION>Sangamon</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Mississippi</LOCATION> rivers.

<PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON>'s formal education consisted of about 18 months of schooling, but he was largely self-educated and an avid reader. He was also a talented local wrestler and skilled with an axe. <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> avoided hunting and fishing because he did not like killing animals, even for food. At 6 foot 4 inches (1.93 m), he was unusually tall, as well as strong.

<PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> began his political career in 1832, at age 23, with an unsuccessful campaign for the <ORGANIZATION>Illinois General Assembly</ORGANIZATION>, as a member of the <ORGANIZATION>Whig Party</ORGANIZATION>. The centerpiece of his platform was the undertaking of navigational improvements on the <LOCATION>Sangamon River</LOCATION>. He believed that this would attract steamboat traffic, which would allow the sparsely populated, poorer areas along the river to flourish.

He was elected captain of an <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION> militia company drawn from <LOCATION>New Salem</LOCATION> during the Black Hawk War, and later wrote that he had not had "any such success in life which gave him so much satisfaction."

For several months, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> ran a small store in <LOCATION>New Salem</LOCATION>. In 1834, he won election to the state legislature, and, after coming across the Commentaries on the Laws of <LOCATION>England</LOCATION>, began to teach himself law. Admitted to the bar in 1837, he moved to <LOCATION>Springfield</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION>, that same year and began to practice law with <PERSON>John T. Stuart</PERSON>. With a reputation as a formidable adversary during cross-examinations and in his closing arguments, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> became an able and successful lawyer.

He served four successive terms in the <ORGANIZATION>Illinois House of Representatives</ORGANIZATION> as a representative from <LOCATION>Sangamon County</LOCATION>, and became a leader of the Illinois Whig party. In 1837, he made his first protest against slavery in the <ORGANIZATION>Illinois House</ORGANIZATION>, stating that the institution was "founded on both injustice and bad policy." It was also in this same year that <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> met <PERSON>Joshua Fry Speed</PERSON>, who would become a close friend.

<PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> wrote a series of anonymous letters, published in 1842 in the <ORGANIZATION>Sangamon Journal</ORGANIZATION>, mocking State Auditor and prominent Democrat <PERSON>James Shields</PERSON>. Two years later, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> entered law practice with <PERSON>William Herndon</PERSON>, a fellow Whig. In 1854, both men joined the fledgling <ORGANIZATION>Republican Party</ORGANIZATION>. Following <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON>'s death, <PERSON>Herndon</PERSON> began collecting stories about <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> and published them in <PERSON>Herndon</PERSON>'s <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON>.



On November 4, 1842 <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> married <PERSON>Mary Todd</PERSON>, daughter of a prominent slave-owning family from <LOCATION>Kentucky</LOCATION>. The couple had four sons. <PERSON>Robert Todd Lincoln</PERSON> was born in <LOCATION>Springfield</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION> on August 1, 1843. Their only child to survive into adulthood, young <PERSON>Robert</PERSON> attended <ORGANIZATION>Phillips Exeter Academy</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Harvard College</ORGANIZATION>.


A Whig and an admirer of party leader <PERSON>Henry Clay</PERSON>, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> was elected to a term in the <ORGANIZATION>U.S. House of Representatives</ORGANIZATION> in 1846. As a freshman House member, he was not a particularly powerful or influential figure. However, he spoke out against the Mexican-American War, which he attributed to President <PERSON>Polk</PERSON>'s desire for "military glory" and challenged the President's claims regarding the <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> boundary and offered Spot Resolutions, demanding to know on what "spot" on <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> soil that blood was first spilt.

<PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> later damaged his political reputation with a speech in which he declared, "God of Heaven has forgotten to defend the weak and innocent, and permitted the strong band of murderers and demons from hell to kill men, women, and children, and lay waste and pillage the land of the just." Two weeks later, President <PERSON>Polk</PERSON> sent a peace treaty to <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION>. While no one in <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> paid any attention to <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON>, the Democrats orchestrated angry outbursts from across his district, where the war was popular and many had volunteered.

Warned by his law partner, <PERSON>William Herndon</PERSON>, that the damage was mounting and irreparable, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> decided not to run for reelection. His statements were not easily forgotten, and would haunt him during the Civil War. These statements were also held against him when he applied for a position in the new <PERSON>Taylor</PERSON> administration. Instead, <PERSON>Taylor</PERSON>'s people offered <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> various positions in the remote <LOCATION>Oregon Territory</LOCATION>, primarily the governorship. Acceptance of this offer would have ended his career in the rapidly growing state of <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION>, so <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> declined the position. Returning to <LOCATION>Springfield</LOCATION>, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> gave up politics for several years and turned his energies to his law practice.

By the mid-1850s, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON>'s caseload focused largely on the competing transportation interests of river barges and railroads. In one prominent 1851 case, he represented the <ORGANIZATION>Alton & Sangamon Railroad</ORGANIZATION> in a dispute with a shareholder, <PERSON>James A. Barret</PERSON>. <PERSON>Barret</PERSON> had refused to pay the balance on his pledge to the railroad on the grounds that it had changed its originally planned route. <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> argued that as a matter of law a corporation is not bound by its original charter when that charter can be amended in the public interest, that the newer route proposed by <ORGANIZATION>Alton & Sangamon</ORGANIZATION> was superior and less expensive, and that accordingly, the corporation had a right to sue <PERSON>Barret</PERSON> for his delinquent payment. He won this case, and the decision by the <ORGANIZATION>Illinois Supreme Court</ORGANIZATION> was eventually cited by several other courts throughout the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION>.

The civil case which won <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> fame as a lawyer was the landmark <ORGANIZATION>Hurd v. Rock Island Bridge Company</ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION>America</LOCATION>'s expansion west, which <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> strongly supported, was seen as an economic threat to the river trade, which ran north-to-south, primarily on the <LOCATION>Mississippi</LOCATION> river. In 1856 a steamboat collided with a bridge, built by the Rock Island Railroad, between <LOCATION>Rock Island</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION>, and <PERSON>Davenport</PERSON>, <LOCATION>Iowa</LOCATION>, the first railroad bridge to span the <LOCATION>Mississippi</LOCATION>. The steamboat owner sued for damages, claiming the bridge was a hazard to navigation. <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> argued in court for the railroad and won, removing a costly impediment to western expansion by establishing the right of land routes to bridge waterways.

Possibly the most notable criminal trial of <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON>'s career as a lawyer came in 1858, when he defended <PERSON>William "Duff" Armstrong</PERSON>, who had been charged with murder. The case became famous for <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON>'s use of judicial notice a rare tactic at that time to show that an eyewitness had lied on the stand. After the witness testified to having seen the crime by moonlight, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> produced a Farmers' Almanac to show that the moon on that date was at such a low angle that it could not have provided enough illumination to see anything clearly. Based almost entirely on this evidence, <PERSON>Armstrong</PERSON> was acquitted.

<PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> was involved in more than 5,100 cases in <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION> alone during his 23-year legal career. Though many of these cases involved little more than filing a writ, others were more substantial and quite involved. <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> and his partners appeared before the <ORGANIZATION>Illinois State Supreme Court</ORGANIZATION> more than 400 times.

<PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> returned to politics in response to the Kansas-Nebraska Act (1854), which expressly repealed the limits on slavery's extent as determined by the Missouri Compromise (1820). <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION> Democrat <PERSON>Stephen A. Douglas</PERSON>, the most powerful man in the <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION>, proposed popular sovereignty as the solution to the slavery impasse, and incorporated it into the <LOCATION>Kansas</LOCATION>-<LOCATION>Nebraska</LOCATION> Act. <PERSON>Douglas</PERSON> argued that in a democracy the people should have the right to decide whether or not to allow slavery in their territory, rather than have such a decision imposed on them by <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION>.

In the October 16, 1854, "<LOCATION>Peoria</LOCATION> Speech", <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> first stood out among the other free soil orators of the day:



Drawing on remnants of the old Whig, <ORGANIZATION>Free Soil</ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION>Liberty</ORGANIZATION> and Democratic parties, he was instrumental in forming the new <ORGANIZATION>Republican Party</ORGANIZATION>. In a stirring campaign, the Republicans carried <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION> in 1854 and elected a senator. <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> was the obvious choice, but to keep the new party balanced he allowed the election to go to an ex-Democrat <PERSON>Lyman Trumbull</PERSON>. At the Republican convention in 1856, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> placed second in the contest to become the party's candidate for Vice-President.

In 1857-58, <PERSON>Douglas</PERSON> broke with President <PERSON>Buchanan</PERSON>, leading to a fight for control of the <ORGANIZATION>Democratic Party</ORGANIZATION>. Some eastern Republicans even favored the reelection of <PERSON>Douglas</PERSON> in 1858, since he had led the opposition to the <ORGANIZATION>Lecompton Constitution</ORGANIZATION>, which would have admitted <LOCATION>Kansas</LOCATION> as a slave state. Accepting the Republican nomination for <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> in 1858, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> delivered his famous speech: "'A house divided against itself cannot stand.'(Mark 3:25) I believe this government cannot endure permanently half slave and half free. I do not expect the Union to be dissolved I do not expect the house to fall but I do expect it will cease to be divided. It will become all one thing, or all the other." The speech created an evocative image of the danger of disunion caused by the slavery debate, and rallied Republicans across the north.

The 1858 campaign featured the Lincoln-Douglas debates, a famous contest on slavery. <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> warned that "The Slave Power" was threatening the values of republicanism, while <PERSON>Douglas</PERSON> emphasized the supremacy of democracy, as set forth in his <ORGANIZATION>Freeport Doctrine</ORGANIZATION>, which said that local settlers should be free to choose whether to allow slavery or not. Though the Republican legislative candidates won more popular votes, the Democrats won more seats, and the legislature reelected <PERSON>Douglas</PERSON> to the <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION>. Nevertheless, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON>'s speeches on the issue transformed him into a national political star.

<PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> was chosen as the <ORGANIZATION>Republican</ORGANIZATION> candidate for the 1860 election for several reasons. His expressed views on slavery were seen as more moderate than those of rivals <PERSON>William H. Seward</PERSON> and <PERSON>Salmon P. Chase</PERSON>. His "Western" origins also appealed to the newer states: other contenders, especially those with more governmental experience, had acquired enemies within the party and were weak in the critical western states, while <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> was perceived as a moderate who could win the West. Most Republicans agreed with <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> that the <PERSON>North</PERSON> was the aggrieved party as the Slave Power tightened its grasp on the national government. Throughout the 1850s he denied that there would ever be a civil war, and his supporters repeatedly rejected claims that his election would incite secession. On May 9-10, 1860, the <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION> Republican State Convention was held in <LOCATION>Decatur</LOCATION>. At this convention, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> received his first endorsement to run for the presidency.

Throughout the general election, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> did not campaign or give speeches. This was handled by the state and county Republican organizations, who used the latest techniques to sustain party enthusiasm and thus obtain high turnout. There was little effort to convert non-Republicans, and there was virtually no campaigning in the South except for a few border cities such as <LOCATION>St. Louis</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Missouri</LOCATION>, and Wheeling, <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION>; indeed, the party did not even run a slate in most of the South. In the North, there were thousands of Republican speakers, tons of campaign posters and leaflets, and thousands of newspaper editorials. These focused first on the party platform, and second on <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON>'s life story, making the most of his boyhood poverty, his pioneer background, his native genius, and his rise from obscurity. His nicknames, "Honest Abe" and "the Rail-Splitter," were exploited to the full. The goal was to emphasize the superior power of "free labor," whereby a common farm boy could work his way to the top by his own efforts.

On November 6, 1860, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> was elected as the 16th President of the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION>, beating Democrat <PERSON>Stephen A. Douglas</PERSON>, <PERSON>John C. Breckinridge</PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION>Southern Democrats</ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON>John Bell</PERSON> of the new <ORGANIZATION>Constitutional Union Party</ORGANIZATION>. He was the first Republican president, winning entirely on the strength of his support in the North: he was not even on the ballot in nine states in the South, and won only 2 of 996 counties in the other Southern states. <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> gained 1,865,908 votes (39.9% of the total), for 180 electoral votes; <PERSON>Douglas</PERSON>, 1,380,202 (29.5%) for 12 electoral votes; <LOCATION>Breckenridge</LOCATION>, 848,019 (18.1%) for 72 electoral votes; and <ORGANIZATION>Bell</ORGANIZATION>, 590,901 (12.5%) for 39 electoral votes. There were fusion tickets in some states, but even if his opponents had combined in every state, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> had a majority vote in all but two of the states in which he won the electoral votes and would still have won the electoral college and the election.

With the emergence of the Republicans as the nation's first major sectional party by the mid-1850s, politics became the stage on which sectional tensions were played out. Although much of the West the focal point of sectional tensions was unfit for cotton cultivation, Southern secessionists read the political fallout as a sign that their power in national politics was rapidly weakening. Before, the slave system had been buttressed to an extent by the <ORGANIZATION>Democratic Party</ORGANIZATION>, which was increasingly seen as representing a more pro-Southern position that unfairly permitted Southerners to prevail in the nation's territories and to dominate national policy before the Civil War. But they suffered a significant reverse in the electoral realignment of the mid-1850s. 1860 was a critical election that marked a stark change in existing patterns of party loyalties among groups of voters; <PERSON>Abraham Lincoln</PERSON>'s election was a watershed in the balance of power of competing national and parochial interests and affiliations.

As <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON>'s election became more likely, secessionists made it clear that their states would leave the Union. On December 20, 1860, <LOCATION>South Carolina</LOCATION> took the lead. By February 1, 1861, <LOCATION>South Carolina</LOCATION> was followed by six other cotton-growing states in the deep <LOCATION>South</LOCATION>. The seven states soon declared themselves to be a new nation, the Confederate States of <LOCATION>America</LOCATION>. The upper South (<LOCATION>Delaware</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Maryland</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>North Carolina</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Tennessee</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Kentucky</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Missouri</LOCATION>, and <LOCATION>Arkansas</LOCATION>) listened to, but initially rejected, the secessionist appeal. President <PERSON>Buchanan</PERSON> and President-elect <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> refused to recognize the Confederacy.

Attempts at compromise, such as the <ORGANIZATION>Crittenden Compromise</ORGANIZATION> which would have extended the Missouri line of 1820, were discussed. Despite support for the Crittenden Compromise among some Republicans, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> denounced it in private letters, saying "either the Missouri line extended, or... Pop. <PERSON>Sov</PERSON>. would lose us everything we gained in the election; that filibustering for all South of us, and making slave states of it, would follow in spite of us, under either plan",while other Republicans publicly stated it "would amount to a perpetual covenant of war against every people, tribe, and state owning a foot of land between here and <LOCATION>Tierra del Fuego</LOCATION> [at the far end of <LOCATION>South America</LOCATION>]."

President-elect <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> evaded possible assassins in <LOCATION>Baltimore</LOCATION>, and on February 23, 1861, arrived in disguise in <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>D.C</LOCATION>.

At his inauguration on March 4, 1861, the German American Turners formed <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON>'s bodyguard; and a sizable garrison of federal troops was also present, ready to protect the capital from Confederate invasion and local insurrection. In his <ORGANIZATION>First Inaugural Address</ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> declared, "I hold that in contemplation of universal law and of the Constitution the Union of these States is perpetual. Perpetuity is implied, if not expressed, in the fundamental law of all national governments," arguing further that the purpose of the <ORGANIZATION>United States Constitution</ORGANIZATION> was "to form a more perfect union" than the Articles of Confederation which were explicitly perpetual, thus the Constitution too was perpetual. He asked rhetorically that even were the Constitution a simple contract, would it not require the agreement of all parties to rescind it?

Also in his inaugural address, in a final attempt to reunite the states and prevent the looming war, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> supported the pending Corwin Amendment to the Constitution, which had already passed <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION>. This amendment, which explicitly protected slavery in those states in which it already existed, had more appeal to the critical border states than to the states that had already declared their separation.


Historian <PERSON>Allan Nevins</PERSON> argues that <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> made three miscalculations in believing that he could preserve the Union, hold government property, and still avoid war. He "temporarily underrated the gravity of the crisis", overestimated the strength of Unionist sentiment in the <LOCATION>South</LOCATION> and border states, and misunderstood the conditional support of Unionists in the border states. In connection with <PERSON>Nevins</PERSON>'s conclusions, it is interesting to note an incident from this period reported in the memoirs of <PERSON>William Tecumseh Sherman</PERSON>. Then a civilian, <PERSON>Sherman</PERSON> visited <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> in the <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> during inauguration week, with his brother, <LOCATION>Ohio</LOCATION> Republican <PERSON>John Sherman</PERSON>. This meeting left the future General <PERSON>Sherman</PERSON> "sadly disappointed" at <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON>'s seeming failure to realize that "the country was sleeping on a volcano" and the South was "'preparing for war.'"


The slave states of <LOCATION>Missouri</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Kentucky</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Maryland</LOCATION>, and <LOCATION>Delaware</LOCATION> did not secede, and <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> urgently negotiated with state leaders there, promising not to interfere with slavery. After the fighting started, he had rebel leaders arrested in all the border areas (especially in <LOCATION>Maryland</LOCATION>) and held in military prisons without trial. Over 18,000 were arrested, though none were executed. One, <PERSON>Clement Vallandigham</PERSON>, was exiled; but all of the remainder were released, usually after two or three months (see: Ex parte <PERSON>Merryman</PERSON>).

In July 1862, <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> moved to free the slaves by passing the Second Confiscation Act. The goal was to weaken the rebellion, which was led and controlled by slave owners. While it did not abolish the legal institution of slavery (the Thirteenth Amendment did that), the Act showed that <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> had the support of <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> in liberating slaves owned by rebels. This new law was implemented with <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON>'s "Emancipation Proclamation."

Ending slavery was always a primary goal of the <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> administration. However, the American public was slow to embrace the idea. In a shrewdly penned letter to <PERSON>Horace Greeley</PERSON>, editor of <ORGANIZATION>The New York Tribune</ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> masked his goal of ending slavery by making it subservient to the cause of preserving the union:



The Emancipation Proclamation, announced on September 22 and put into effect on January 1, 1863, freed slaves in territories not under Union control. As Union armies advanced south, more slaves were liberated until all of them in Confederate hands (over three million) were freed. <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> later said: "I never, in my life, felt more certain that I was doing right, than I do in signing this paper." The proclamation made the abolition of slavery in the rebel states an official war goal. <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> then threw his energies into passage of the Thirteenth Amendment to permanently abolish slavery throughout the nation.

In September 1862, thirteen northern governors met in <LOCATION>Altoona</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION>, at the Loyal War Governors' Conference to discuss the Proclamation and Union war effort. In the end, the state executives fully supported the president's Proclamation and also suggested the removal of General <PERSON>George B. McClellan</PERSON> as commander of the Union's Army of the <LOCATION>Potomac</LOCATION>.

For some time, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> continued earlier plans to set up colonies for the newly freed slaves. He commented favorably on colonization in the Emancipation Proclamation, but all attempts at such a massive undertaking failed. As <PERSON>Frederick Douglass</PERSON> observed, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> was, "The first great man that I talked with in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> freely who in no single instance reminded me of the difference between himself and myself, of the difference of color."


Writing to <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> in September 1863, the Governor of <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION>, <PERSON>Andrew Curtin</PERSON>, warned that political sentiments were turning against <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> and the war effort:



At the dedication of the Soldiers' National Cemetery in <LOCATION>Gettysburg</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION>, on November 19, beginning with the now-iconic phrase "Four score and seven years ago...", <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> referred to the events of the Civil War and described the ceremony at <LOCATION>Gettysburg</LOCATION> as an opportunity not only to dedicate the grounds of a cemetery, but also to consecrate the living in the struggle to ensure that "government of the people, by the people, for the people, shall not perish from the earth".

After Union victories at <LOCATION>Gettysburg</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Vicksburg</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Chattanooga</LOCATION> in 1863, overall victory seemed at hand, and <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> promoted <PERSON>Ulysses S. Grant</PERSON> General-in-Chief ( March 12, 1864). When the spring campaigns turned into bloody stalemates, <PERSON>Lincoln</PERSON> supported <PERSON>Grant</PERSON>'s strategy of wearing down <PERSON>Lee</PERSON>'s Confederate army at the cost of heavy Union casualties. With an election looming, he easily defeated efforts to deny his renomination. At the Convention, the <ORGANIZATION>Republican Party</ORGANIZATION> selected <PERSON>Andrew Johnson</PERSON>, a War Democrat from the Southern state of <LOCATION>Tennessee</LOCATION>, as his running mate in order to form a broader coalition. They ran on the new <ORGANIZATION>Union Party</ORGANIZATION> ticket uniting Republicans and War Democrats.


